<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: cloud computing | Voodoo Tiki God]]></title>
  <link href="http://voodootikigod.github.com/blog/categories/cloud-computing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://voodootikigod.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-16T21:02:57-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://voodootikigod.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris Williams]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing NoSQL East 2009]]></title>
    <link href="http://voodootikigod.github.com/announcing-nosql-east-2009/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://voodootikigod.github.com/announcing-nosql-east-2009</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today <a href="http://twitter.com/boorad">Brad Anderson</a>&nbsp;from <a href="http://cloudant.com/">Cloudant</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/mattpodwysocki">Matthew Podwysocki</a> from <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/">Microsoft</a>, and myself announced the first ever <a href="http://nosqleast.com/2009/">NoSQL East</a> conference to be held October 28th - 30th, 2009 in Atlanta, GA. This conference will be the extension of the very successful and&nbsp;highly disruptive&nbsp;<a href="http://nosql.eventbrite.com/">NoSQL meetup</a> held June 11th, 2009 in San Francisco - we just couldn't let "The Valley" have all the fun! Brad and I have been discussing this event for quite some time so it is great to see it finally launch and begin to announce it to everyone. The main focus of the conference will be highly scalable, non-relational databases of all sorts and variety, but the most important part of the event will be gathering people like you together. We are bringing together some of the brightest minds we can get access to and &nbsp;providing them a podium to present their ideas and technologies to you. This event will definitely blow your mind if you haven't had the chance to dabble with any of the various non-relational&nbsp;<span style="background-color: #ffffff;">databases and it will definitely be the greatest learning opportunity for anyone working with or near "Big Data". Check out the highly impressive <a href="http://nosqleast.com/2009/#speakers">list of confirmed speakers</a> that will present on topics ranging from <a href="http://mongodb.org/">MongoDB</a> to <a href="http://couchdb.apache.org/">CouchDB</a> to <a href="http://incubator.apache.org/cassandra/">Cassandra</a> and the recently released <a href="http://riak.basho.com/">Riak</a>. If you are a programmer, regardless of your language of choice, this conference is for you!</span></p>


<p><span style="background-color: #ffffff;"> <a href="http://nosqleast.com/2009/#register">Register today, tickets are going fast</a>!</span></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
